decide what I want to talk about is a
foundational economic concept maybe
financial concept depending on your
preference so the notion is this
remember we've taken the idea in the
city we've separated the virtual and the
physical into and decouple them into two
different objects now what I'd like you
to use I imagine a landscape and then
give it hills and valleys and then
imagine rain that falls evenly on the
landscape now we're gonna call that that
rain value and what we'll notice is that
like rain falling on a on a valley the
the water will tend to slide down from
the hills and gather in the valleys turn
into rivers then eventually pour into a
pond or a lake if the landscape is
appropriately shaped as it turns out the
same sort of thing happens with value
and so in the context of the physical in
the context of the physical side of the
city um the thing we call real estate
land might be thought of as being a low
point in the attractor space of value
distribution and what this means is that
if you were to measure the distribution
of value in an economy the owners of
real estate will actually tend to accrue
a disproportionate share more than their
fair share to the point particularly
visa vie the amount of data they
actually generate into the economy so
the eyes that's produced in the economy
will have more return to real estate
than it will to other locations higher
up on the stack of the economy the same
thing is true by the way in the virtual
domain although it's a little bit more
abstract so if you imagine like in the
old PC ecosystem for those if you were
old enough to remember that you had all
these applications like Word Excel and I
guess web browsers and these were the
value these are the things that people
wanted games but the value actually a
nerd mostly to the operating system and
that's the equivalent of real estate in
the early internet and ended up
ultimately being search so yeah and then
Google and then in web 2.0 ended up
being the sort of the social media
platform
Twitter YouTube Facebook and what you
might say is that in the virtual space
it is the the most basic cynic went on
or cannot do without aspect of what
makes Metcalfe's law work what makes the
network effect a network effect so the
lower you can go in the stack to get to
the point where an individual joining
creates a network effect and then and
then have applications sit on top of
that that thing that platform is the
place that is the virtual equivalent of
real-estate value will tend to
disproportionately collect in that
location and then if you can own that if
you can have a property ownership of it
you will actually end up extracting
value from the larger economy they will
float to you disproportionate to the
amount of data that you're putting in so
we can say for example that as a sort of
a basic rule principle of design that
there should be a symmetry rule in terms
of value meaning if I produce X in value
I should have X and ie return to me
neither more nor less and so for
therefore for example I'm well oriented
in in where in how effective my choices
are right if I produce X and I get less
the next and I'm actually going to be
doing less of what is actually valuable
because I'm not feeling the value of
myself and vice-versa alright if I'd if
I'd if I do X and I get more than X then
I'll actually be wasting my time
everybody else's time by doing something
section not as valuable I perceive it to
be so there's a good basic principle now
what we noticed is that because of the
topology of these value landscapes sorry
topography of these i/o landscapes
owning land has a characteristic of much
more than X and I put a certain amount
of value into the economy but I get
actually substantially more than that
back so this will disproportionately
cause people to seek owning land
same thing with owning platforms it
creates the wrong kinds of feedback
loops so in the context of Scythian what
we will have is a rule very basic at the
foundational level that these two
objects and if others like this are
discovered must be held as a common
so that it cannot be held or owned by
any particular actor the the value that
collects in these value attractors has
to be looped back out and distributed
pro rata to each value creator that
actually creates a symmetry and
therefore Orient's the choice making of
the larger community more effectively so
what that means practically is that if
you were a citizen if you're a full
member of the city 'm you will have a
pro rata share in all of the land and a
pro rata share of the foundational
technical platform and that were more of
us return to you on a continuing basis
the value that accrues to those
locations will then be redistributed to
everybody who's the symmetric member
spoiler alert this will look a lot like
UVI
as you go forward